<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loud Capital</title>
    <link>https://zeraceee.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Loud Capital</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 10:09:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zeraceee.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Intention &amp; Entrepreneurship</title>
      <link>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/do-no-harm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 10:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/do-no-harm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve found myself comparing the structured medical field to the unstructured entrepreneurial space. It is not only a comparison that runs through my head, but it is also the life I have been living for the past few years. My life experiences are rooted in these two worlds, and give me a unique vantage point that allows me to compare the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been practicing anesthesiology for the past ten years in a large hospital and outpatient based practice. As many may know, the path to becoming a physician in the U.S. is quite arduous and lengthy; It takes patience, determination, sacrifice, and the desire to be a doctor. It took four years of undergrad, four years of medical school, and four years of residency in anesthesiology before I could work independently and make medical decisions that were based on my knowledge and critical thinking. Over the years, my medical colleagues and I have dealt with challenging patient cases which were both expected and what we trained for. What we have spent more time on unexpectedly, were the ever-changing policies and procedures that our medical associations, hospital health systems, insurance companies, and various other stakeholders expected us to follow. These policies are sometimes motivated politically, financially, or scientifically; however, they often lack the crucial contribution of a well-trained physician, one of the primary agents that these decisions directly affect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educational event where our first company, SmileMD, continues to bring safety standards to the dental community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, I have been an entrepreneur for almost 4 years. When I say entrepreneur, I mean I took direct action to follow one of my ideas. I know many of you can relate to recognizing great ideas and thoughts, but following through is a whole other animal to overcome. It was 4 years ago when I decided to seize an opportunity and co-found my first company. When we founded our first company (I have founded 2 companies up to date and it’s always been with other co-founders), I had no clue about what entrepreneurship entailed. I was caught off guard by the lack of structure, the amount of risks, the unpredictable timeline, and the uncertain pathways. Not to mention the daunting task of recruiting the right people that align with your vision and can get things done; no amount of degrees can shed light on the ability or skill sets of an individual or how they’d work within the team. The diversity of the entrepreneurial world is incredible. It can range from a driven high school kid with a big idea and a dream all the way up to a seasoned corporate executive looking to pursue a passion that was kept on the backburner for years. In between all this are a whole world of people with different intentions, moral compasses, and a range of goals. It’s an open world that creates excitement, uncertainty, and provides freedom and a creative landscape of which I have never experienced before. The descriptions can be a bit dramatic but so was coming from a structured medical environment and jumping into a completely different world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to explain the knowledge and best practices that I have experienced and apply them to this unstructured entrepreneurial ecosystem. I happen to be a glass half-full kind of guy so my intention is to come up with some ideas that improve this exciting and kind of chaotic world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I absolutely love about medicine is the intention — we intend to help patients, we intend to do no harm, we intend to treat all the patients equally in a very professional and respectful manner. Is this a text book?? No, it’s not and nor am I saying that all physicians are super human or even that all physicians live by these words. I can tell you that these things always enter my mind when I’m at work. Have I executed on all three above things all the time? No, I haven’t but my intention is to do so. When we are in medical school, we take a Hippocratic Oath to “do no harm.” The simplicity of the message has always stuck with me, as serves as a significant guide when making medical decisions. Why is it that only physicians take this oath and it’s not an oath that we adopt from a much earlier age?? By knowing the oath and understanding the intentions of physicians, it provides for common goals while at work. Yes, sometimes we want to leave early, and hang out with family and friends, but if we are at work we all have an understanding to help patients; first do no harm, and treat all patients with respect and professionalism. It’s one of the few guidelines that can be accessed while faced with challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I absolutely love about entrepreneurship is the opportunity for the creatives. What? Isn’t it all about business?? Possibly, for some, but not from my perspective. I love that you can come up with your own idea, involve anyone you want, build anything you want, make it look and smell like anything you want, put as much time or as little time as you want, spend nothing or a ton of money on it, and most of all, let your passion lead the way through barriers that really don’t exist…. One can push the ceiling higher, or just open it up to stare at the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In getting to the point, I have figured out that to continue to perfect the world of entrepreneurship, we must first “do no harm.” We should align our goals with the people/team around us, we should be extremely creative and push innovative pathways, and we shouldn’t let barriers that others have put up, stop us. We should also be respectful and professional to our partners, clients, and anyone we work with. We should have a variety of goals that are ambitious while also benefiting customers and society. Although entrepreneurs come in all shapes and sizes, following a couple of those guidelines while white boarding, or having “thinking out loud” sessions, can provide tremendous value to our society. I do know this. I take these guidelines that the medical field has instilled in me and apply it to the beautifully creative entrepreneurial ecosystem. I’m personally just getting started, but I hope that others can consider this practice as well. It’s another day, another opportunity, and another chance to take entrepreneurship and amplify it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the creatives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the disciplined&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to encouraging others to take that first step&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to Entrepreneurship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LOUD Capital. Entrepreneurship. Amplified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zeraceee.github.io/uploads/2017/03/10/LOUDCapitalTeam.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Hard Truths About UGC</title>
      <link>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/medium-title-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/medium-title-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you spend every waking moment for the past two years thinking about user-generated content as it relates to customer engagement, you start to look at the world a little differently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, since starting BYLINED I now see the world through the lens of engagement, reach, ROI, usage rights, and metadata. Especially usage rights and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see campaigns like the “Shot on iPhone 6” campaign that are incredibly engaging and inspiring. I also see influencer marketing campaigns gone wrong or read about brands inappropriately using photos without permission and ask myself “What in the world were they thinking?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thousands of hours researching and interviewing brands and their customers, here are the 5 hard truths behind UGC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. UGC campaigns today squarely benefit networks and not brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UGC campaigns can certainly help brands generate a bit of reach, some can even hypothesize an ROI around reach. However, when you consider all of the effort brands put into driving user-generated content… the thousands of hours spent creating #hashtagcampaigns… the tens of thousands of dollars spent on #influencermarketing campaigns… unfortunately, all of the work involved in the current process for driving UGC is largely for naught in the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When brands run UGC campaigns on social networks, they are effectively giving away all of the content they worked so hard to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Permission : Implied Usage Consent vs Explicit Usage Consent &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One workaround to the issue of UGC ownership is to create the illusion of implied usage consent through the creation of hashtag campaigns. When fans and customers submit photos to hashtags, there’s an implied usage consent between the creator of the photo and the brand hosting the hashtag campaign. However, again that consent is implied and not explicit consent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some brands will go as far as personally reaching out to their fans who post content to their hashtags, requesting explicit usage consent to reuse photos, particularly those photos that focus on an identifiable person (or model) and as a result, the brand would also request a model release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As content creating customers become increasingly aware of the value of their content, brands will need to have the systems in place to support the collection of UGC with explicit usage consent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BYLINED Photo Submission by Nick Skiles for “Jeep Adventure” Assignment. 3. “May we use this photo?” vs “Did you take this photo?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With either scenario (implied consent vs explicit consent), it’s not the platform that hosted the hashtag campaign that owns the copyright. It’s also not the fan that posted content to the hashtag campaign. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the person who actually took the photo that owns the rights to the photo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many earned content platforms work with brands to request explicit consent by asking the question “May we use your photo?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question brands must ask is “Did you take this photo?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. Brands ultimately don’t own their metadata&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright ownership ultimately belongs to the person who actually took the photo, the only surefire way to confirm ownership is through EXIF (Exchangeable Image File) metadata. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of an EXIF file as a fingerprint. No two are the same and they can provide incredibly valuable information behind each photo including ownership, provide a date stamp, time stamp, location stamp, image size, file size, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metadata can also provide brands with deep insights into customer buying habits as well the information necessary to build email lists and highly effective retargeting campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, when brands capture UGC from social platforms, they don’t capture or own the metadata behind the UGC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in an AdAge article on this subject, “if content is king, its metadata is heir to the throne.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Authenticity &amp;gt; endorsement deals &amp;amp; the Instafamous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of signing Hollywood stars for endorsement deals, paying influential style bloggers, and hiring Insta-famous celebs are far from endangered, but for many brands the realness and authenticity of everyday customer stories to enhance brand awareness and influence purchasing decisions holds incredibly powerful potential. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, smart consumers want to buy from brands that speak and interact as everyday humans, not celebrities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: Creating, owning and monetizing authentic UGC &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every brand on this planet as well as their customers have the opportunity to monetize UGC in a meaningful way. The key to monetization for brands lies in a their ability to own (vs earn) their UGC. And as their content-creating customers become more aware of the value of their content, they too should have the opportunity to monetize their UGC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal at BYLINED is to bridge the gap between the brands in need of fantastic UGC and their content-creating fans who want to be a part of a brand and it’s story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we at peak stock photography?</title>
      <link>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/are-we-at-peak-stock-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeraceee.github.io/blog/are-we-at-peak-stock-photography/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zeraceee.github.io/realestate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zeraceee.github.io/realestate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&#34;{{ with .Site.LanguageCode }}{{ . }}{{ else }}en-US{{ end }}&#34;&gt;

  {{ partial &#34;head.html&#34; . }}

  &lt;body id=&#34;page-top&#34; class=&#34;index&#34;&gt;
    {{ partial &#34;rs-hero.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;rs-about.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;rs-team.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;rs-portfolio.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;rs-contact.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;footer.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;modals.html&#34; . }}
    {{ partial &#34;js.html&#34; . }}
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>